<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The World is Hybrid on Vr̥ddhi</title>
    <link>https://vrddhi.xyz/docs/the-world-is-hybrid/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The World is Hybrid on Vr̥ddhi</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vrddhi.xyz/docs/the-world-is-hybrid/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What inspired this work?</title>
      <link>https://vrddhi.xyz/docs/the-world-is-hybrid/prologue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vrddhi.xyz/docs/the-world-is-hybrid/prologue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-inspired-this-work&#34;&gt;&#xA;  What inspired this work?&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#what-inspired-this-work&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Four things.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tesla CEO&amp;rsquo;s rant that hybrid cars don&amp;rsquo;t make sense. Yes, this work was inspired by a talk about hybrid cars, although it is not about hybrid cars. See the irony!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My experience with data structures in computer systems during my Ph.D. journey.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Discussions on the philosophy and spread of monotheistic religions by different people and recalling my own experiences in this regard. If you can recall Yuval Noah Harari&amp;rsquo;s Sapiens (Chapter 12. The Law of Religion), you can proably guess what I am talking about.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where do hybrid systems exist?</title>
      <link>https://vrddhi.xyz/docs/the-world-is-hybrid/definition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vrddhi.xyz/docs/the-world-is-hybrid/definition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;draft-where-do-hybrid-systems-exist&#34;&gt;&#xA;  [Draft] Where do hybrid systems exist?&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#draft-where-do-hybrid-systems-exist&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In contemporary American consumers&amp;rsquo; mind, the word &amp;ldquo;hybrid&amp;rdquo; is likely to trigger the image of a hybrid car. The reason these cars are called hybrid is because of their dual power source - gasoline engine and electric motor, in this case. The hybrid system can also exist in fuel sources. Early generation hybrid cars used only gasoline as fuel. Newer plug-in hybrids can use both gasoline and external electric power source. If we zoom out and look at the fuel types used by the regular cars globally, then we also find a hybrid setup. Some cars use diesel, some cars use unleaded gasoline (i.e., petrol and octane), some cars use electricity. Using a single type of fuel for all cars in the world seems unreasonable due to efficiency variance of different fuel types. Hence, a hybrid fuel system existed from the early days of cars. At this point, we can zoom out a little more and look at fuel types of different types of vehicles. Passenger cars, commerical buses, ships, aircrafts, and locomotives use different types fuels and power sources. Hybrid systems have always existed. It is just a matter of perspective and scope! Hybrid systems can exist globally, even if individual components of the system are not hybrid. Local hybrid systems can also exist, even if the global system is not hybrid. Hybrid systems can also be hyper-local!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
